CONTACT

Chennai, India



+91 90945 36176



davidimmanuelsn.95@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Quantitative Methods
- Data Warehousing
- Advanced Data Mining
- Business Intelligence (BI)
- Data Structures
- Regression Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Data Technologies
- Data Science Research Methods
- Research Data Management
- Statistical Computing Methods
- Experimental Design & Analysis

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- SPSS
- R Studio
- Tableau
- · SOL
- Advanced Excel
- KNIME

U - S

David Immanuel N

Business Analyst | Data Analyst Professional

SUMMARY

Proficient and dynamic data analysis professional with 2+ years of experience in highly analytical and process-oriented data analysis with in-depth knowledge of database types; research methodologies; and big data capture, curation, manipulation and visualization. Furnish insights, analytics and business intelligence used to advance opportunity identification, process reengineering and corporate growth.

EXPERIENCE

FreeLancer • Dec 2022 – Present Data Analyst / Finance Consultant

- Steered as Data Analyst responsible for managing the Finance team for seamless transition and Business continuity.
- Administered ENPS Survey to measure employee satisfaction and loyalty.
 Provided insights to improve the health of the business in terms of customer satisfaction and internal operations.
- Developed financial planning and budgeting models, conducted variance analysis and prepared management reporting for large enterprise requirements.
- Worked closely with client stakeholders as an extended financial planning and reporting resource for Client team.
- Deal with large volumes of granular data, understand trends and patterns to arrive at business outcomes for client.

Senior Finance Associate • Aug 2021 – Nov 2022 Intellisery Technologies Private Limited

- Led as Senior Finance Associate handling client management, business development and finance management.
- Referred unresolved customer grievances or special requests to the designation department for further investigations. Followed up to ensure that appropriate actions were taken on customers' requests.
- Created a Dashboard to highlight the performance of each Account Expert and was able to increase the Average sales rate per product by 24%.
- Established own goals and of the team to match corporate goals, short term and long-term budgets and developing business plans for the achievement of these goals.
- Formulated business plan for development and growth of the organization.
 Steered entire business directions, ensuring profitability in line with organizational objectives.

LOCATIONS



EDUCATION

PGDM (Analytics), JAGSOM Business School – CGPA 6.79/10.00

BE (Electronics & Instrumentation), St. Joseph's College of Engineering, April 2017

12th, Kings MHSS, Tirunelveli, April 2013, 81.16%

10th, St. Ann's MHSS, Tirunelveli, April 2011, 81%

COURSE

- Deep Learning A-Z's Hands-on Artificial Neural Networks Course (2020)
- Python for Machine Learning certification from Great Learning Academy (2020)
- Master Tableau in Data Science course from Udemy (2020)
- Microsoft Access SQL, Database Design and MySQL course from IsáBel (2020)
- Foundations of Data Science course from Padhai One Series (2020)
- Master Data Science in Python certification from Great Learning Academy (2020)

Content Analyst Internship • Feb 2021 - Jul 2021

LSEG Group

- Responsible for creation of dashboard with team members to optimize key performance indicators and project accomplishment.
- Evaluated numerous reports and classified them with distinct metadata.
 Maintained a high level of productivity and accuracy on individual projects.
- Collaborated with team members for overall group success. Respond to requests to investigate content related issues, identify root cause, and remediate.
- Conducted and participated in peer reviews to ensure product/feature quality.
- Provided regular updates on progress and delays encountered during development of content and frameworks.

PRECEDING EXPERIENCE

Annai Fibers

Inventory Manager Aug 2017 - Apr 2019

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Steered the Routes and Races team of "Kanyathon 5 /10km marathon", To Save the Girl Child 2020, hosted by IFIM.
- Organized and led "Quiz Night, STATISTA 2k19" in 2019 Fest organized by Data Analytics Committee - IFIM Institutions.
- State Level Kings Tournament Winner in Basketball (2013).
- Conducted Basketball Summer Coaching Camps for over 50 players varying from the age of 9-17 years.
- Increased the Average Quarterly Sales in the Company by 24% by creating a Interactive Dashboard.
- Reduced the Cost of Insurance Coverage for employees in the company by 11% by doing market research and negotiating a better deal.